Reza Shami Tanha

Personal Information

Surname Shami Tanha

Name Reza

Date and Place of Birth February 25, 1996; Zanjan, Iran

Nationality Iranian

Email reza.sh.tanha.study@gmail.com

Address Room 123, Department of Computer Science and IT, Institute for Advanced Studies in

Basic Sciences (IASBS), 444 Prof. Yousef Sobouti Blvd., Zanjan 45137-66731, Iran

Phone (+98) 919 679 7553

Website rezashami.github.io

Linked ID reza-tanha-112807110

GitHub github.com/rezashami

Skype ID reza.sht

SUMMARY

I am a Master's graduate of computer science from the Institute for Advanced Studies in Basic Sciences (IASBS). I'm researching employing machine learning tools, especially graph neural networks, in bioinformatics problems. I am also researching finding a way for cooperative teamwork among robotic agents and formulating physical phenomena as mathematical models to prepare an acting environment for agents.

EDUCATION

Institute for Advanced Studies in Basic Sciences (IASBS).

Zanjan, Iran

MSc in Artificial Intelligence, GPA: 16.72/20.00

2019-2023

- Thesis: "Firefighting by Autonomous UAVs Network using Deep Reinforcement Learning"
- Suprevisors: Dr. Mohsen Afsharchi, Dr. Mohsen Hooshmand

Institute for Advanced Studies in Basic Sciences (IASBS).

Zanjan, Iran

B.S. in Information Technology (IT), GPA: 15.94/20.00

2014-2018

- Thesis: "Designing and Implementing A Mobile Phone System to Remind when to Take Medicine"
- Suprevisor: Dr. Ebrahim Ansari

Research Interests

- Machine Learning
- Reinforcement Learning
- Multi Agent Reinforcement Learning
- Graph Neural Networks

PUBLICATIONS

- [1] R. Shami Tanha, M. Sadighian, A. Zabihian, M. Hooshmand, and M. Afsharchi, "MAD-TI: Meta-path aggregated-graph attention network for drug target interaction prediction", presented at the 2023 31st International Conference on Electrical Engineering (ICEE), 2023.
- [2] A. Zabihian, F. Z. Sayyad, S. M. Hashemi, R. Shami Tanha, M. Hooshmand, and S. Gharaghani, "DEDTI vs IEDTI: Efficient and predictive models of drug-target interactions", *Scientific Reports*, vol. 13, pp. 1–18, 2023. [Online]. Available: https://doi.org/10.1038/s41598-023-36438-0.

Relevant Graduate Courses Passed

- Machine Learning, 2020
 - Bishop, Christopher M. (2006). "Pattern recognition and machine learning". New York :Springer,
- Advanced Data Mining, 2020
 - Han, J., Kamber, M. & Pei, J. (2012). "Data mining concepts and techniques", third edition Morgan
- Deep Learning, 2020
 - Bengio, Y. (2016). "Deep Learning". MIT Press.
- Advanced Artificial Intelligence, 2019
 - Russell S. J. & Norvig P. (2010). "Artificial intelligence: a modern approach (3rd ed.)". Pearson.
- Multi Agent Systems, 2020
 - Wooldridge, M. (2009). "An introduction to multiagent systems". John wiley & sons.

EXPERIENCES

•	Research Assistant at IASBS, Departement of Computer Sciences and IT Supervisor: Dr. Mohsen Hooshmand	May 2023 - August 2023
•	Freelancer Website Developer Develop and maintain an online questionnaire website, online.iran.liara.run	January 2023 - April 2023

TEACHING

• Teaching Assistant at IASBS, Departement of Computer Sciences and IT Course name: Reinforcement Learning, Teacher: Dr. Mohsen Hooshmand	Fall 2022
• Teaching Assistant at IASBS, Departement of Computer Sciences and IT Course name: Advanced Data Mining, Teacher: Dr. Zahra Narimani	Winter 2022
• Teaching Assistant at IASBS, Departement of Computer Sciences and IT Course name: Multi Agent Systems, Teacher: Dr. Mohsen Afsharchi	Winter 2021
• Teaching Assistant at IASBS, Departement of Computer Sciences and IT Course name: Advanced Programming, Teacher: Dr. Ebrahim Ansari	Spring 2017
• Teaching Assistant at IASBS, Departement of Computer Sciences and IT Course name: Data Structures, Teacher: Dr. Mehdi Khosravian	Winter 2016
• Teaching Assistant at IASBS, Departement of Computer Sciences and IT Course name: Basic Programming, Teacher: Dr. Ebrahim Ansari	Fall 2015

COMPUTER SKILLS

Programming languages:

- C++ (expert)
- Python (expert)
- JavaScript (experienced)
- Java (good knowledge)

Back-End:

- Node.JS (experienced)
- Express.JS (experienced)
- PHP (experienced)
- XAMP (experienced)

Databases:

- MongoDB (good knowledge)
- MySQL (experienced)

Operation Systems:

- Linux
- Windows

Machine Learning and Deep Learning:

- PyTorch, TensorFlow
- NumPy, SciPy, Keras, Pandas
- Matplotlib

Front-End:

- Html, CSS, JavaScript (experienced)
- Bootstrap (experienced)
- jQuery (experienced)

Scientific software:

• MATLAB (experienced)

Others:

- LATEX(good knowledge)
- Heroku (good knowledge)
- Git (experienced)
- Express JS and mongoose libraries in Node.JS

LANGUAGE SKILLS

Persian: NativeAzari: Native

• English: Intermediate

Conferences and Seminars Attended

- Computational methods for modelling bionano interactions and nanomaterials functionality workshop (26 –28 June2023, CECAM-IRL-Online), https://www.cecam.org/workshop-details/1231
- 31st International Conference on Electrical Engineering (ICEE) (9–11 MAY 2023, Electrical Engineering Department, Amirkabir University of Technology), https://iceeconf.ir/2023
- Fifth IPM Advanced School On Computing & Artificial Intelligence (5–8 SEP 2021, Online)
- PyTorch Workshop (4–7 SEP 2021, Computer Science Department, IASBS)

Interests and Hobbies

- · Reading books
- Traveling

REFERENCES

• Dr. Mohsen Hooshmand

Institute for Advanced Studies in Basic Sciences (IASBS), Zanjan, Iran Assistant Professor

- Thesis supervisor
- Email: mohsen.hooshmand@iasbs.ac.ir
- Website: https://iasbs.ac.ir/~mohsen.hooshmand

• Dr. Zahra Narimani

Institute for Advanced Studies in Basic Sciences (IASBS), Zanjan, Iran Assistant Professor

- Email: narimani@iasbs.ac.ir
- Website: https://iasbs.ac.ir/~narimani